谁想吃最后一个饺子
Who wants the last dumpling?
我来吃
Ooh, me!
佩妮  等等
Penny, a moment.
我们刚吃了泰国料理
We just had Thai food.
在泰国文化中  最后一口食物
In that culture, the last morsel is called
被称为"Greng宰"  它应该被赏赐给
the "Greng Jai" piece, and it is reserved for
一群人中最重要最有价值的那个人
the most important and valued member of the group.
感谢大家给予我这么高的殊荣
Thank you all for this high honor.
我见识到了令堂曾经的影子  您继续吃吧
I've seen pictures of your mother, keep eating.
好了亲爱的  如果我们要看电影  现在就该走了
All right, honey, if we're gonna make the movie, we should go.
这话你可能不喜欢听
This may be hard for you to hear,
我说的"亲爱的"  指的是我的未婚妻
but when I say "honey," I mean my fiance.
我懂  起码现在指的是她了
Yeah, well, now it means her.
他想来也没关系的
It's okay if he wants to come.
好吧  但下次我们得找个保姆了
Fine. But next time, we get a sitter.
好了  我也得上班了
All right, I got to go to work.
-我跟你们一起走  -等下
- I'll walk down with you.  - Wait.
你们谁的目的地离蒙罗维亚新开的玩具火车店近些
Which is closer to the new train store in Monrovia,
电影院还是芝士工厂
the movie theater or The Cheesecake Factory?
哪个都不近
Neither of them are close.
这样一来  想必你们谁送我去
Oh, well, then I guess it doesn't matter
都没有太大关系了
which one of you drives me.
我们玩个有趣的猜谜游戏
Let's play a fun guessing game
来决定谁送我去吧
to see who gets to take me.
开始了  这个四字母单词既描述了
All right, this four-letter word describes either
一个打印机的字号  又描述了一种强迫受辱的行为
a printer's type size or a compulsion to eat dirt.
事先声明  我才不送他去呢
Okay, I'm not driving him.
佩妮别放弃啊  这个你猜的出
Penny, don't give up, you can get this.
你不跟谢尔顿一起去吗
Aren't you going with Sheldon?
不了  我对火车模型
No, I have no interest in model trains,
火车模型商店和令店主崩溃的老主顾都不感兴趣
stores that sell them, nor their heartbreaking clientele.
我还有点工作要做  所以...
Well, I have some work to do, so...
我不觉得那会妨碍到我
I can't imagine that would disturb me.
你继续
Carry on.
好吧
Okay.
你在自己家不会更自在些吗
Wouldn't you be more comfortable at home?
不觉得  不会
Not really, no.
那好吧
All righty then.
我猜我现在要开始干活了
Guess I'll just get started.
莱纳德  拜托  我不需要实况报道
Leonard, please. I don't need the running commentary.
-艾米  -在
- Amy?   - Yo.
你还好吗
You okay?
当然
Oh, sure.
我以为你在读书呢
I thought you were reading.
之前在读
I was.
现在我在思索之前读的内容
Now I'm thinking about what I read.
你还好吗  莱纳德
You all right, Leonard?
你看起来坐立不安
You seem very uncomfortable.
我...  我很好
I-I'm fine.
我是不是该离开了
Should I go?
我有时会被告知自己作客时间过久
I've been told sometimes I overstay my welcome.
谁...  谁跟你这么说过呀
Wha... who told you that?
最近一次是我的妇科医生
Well, most recently my gynecologist.
你想待多久就待多久
Well, you stay as long as you'd like.
我很高兴听到你这么说
I'm glad to hear you say that,
因为我现在待的很开心
because I'm having a wonderful time.
我跟我妇科医生也这么说
I said the same thing to my gynecologist.
你打算去商店里买点什么呢  谢尔顿
What are you going to get at the train store, Sheldon?
我什么都不打算买
Oh, I'm not buying anything.
它们那儿要办一个讲座
They're having a lecture.
"HO轨距的铁路发展
"H-O gauge railroading.
O轨距一半的尺寸  却能带来双倍的欢乐"
Half the size of O-gauge, but twice the fun."
非常有争议性的题目
Very controversial topic.
你支持哪一种轨距呢
Which side do you come down on?
今晚过后我会让你知道
I'll let you know after tonight.
不像某些人  起码我会带着开放的态度去听
Unlike some people, I'm going in with an open mind.
不过这不是玩笑嘛
Who am I kidding?
显而易见  O轨距铁路  舍O其谁
Of course we all know it's O-gauge or no gauge.
你能相信一个成年男性还坐在那玩玩具火车吗
Can you believe grown men sit around and play with toy trains?
对于一位自己的母亲家中
That's pretty big talk for a man
还藏着满柜子的魔术把戏的男人而言  那算很成熟了
with a closet full of magic tricks at his mother's house.
首先  那不是把戏  那都是我的"幻想"
First of all, they're not tricks, they're illusions.
其次...
And...
其次  当我们结婚后  那些玩意都会被
secondly, when we get married, they're all going up
扔进阁楼里  这样你就能有衣柜放衣服了
in the attic so you can have that closet for clothes.
我为何要放衣服在你妈妈的房子里
Why would I keep clothes at your mother's house?
你也别这么想嘛
Well, don't think of it that way.
我们搬进去后  那就是我们的房子了
Once we move in, it'll be our house.
你妈会搬出来吗
Is she moving out?
她为何要搬啊
Why would she move out?
那是她的房子啊
It's her house.
你等等
Hang on.
你难道真以为我会同意和你妈妈住一起吗
You seriously think I'm going to live with your mother?
霍华德  我想这个问题我可以回答
Howard, I think I can help here.
是的  伯纳黛特  他就是这么想的
Yes, Bernadette, that's exactly what he thinks.
为何不住一起呢
Why not?
那是个好房子  很多屋子
It's a great house, plenty of room,
如果我们有了孩子  我妈妈还能帮忙
and if we have kids, Mom's there to help.
当然  当她讲"三只小猪"的故事时
You know, when she tells "The Three Little Pigs" story,
她的下巴上是真的有胡子的
she actually has hair on her chinny-chin-chin.
我才不和你妈住一起呢
I'm not gonna live with your mother.
现在不会  以后也不会
Not now, not ever.
显然是有人和妈咪相处得不好
Wow, someone obviously has some mommy issues.
拉杰  送我回家
Raj, take me home.
别听她的  去电影院
Don't listen to her. Go to the movie theater.
赶紧送我回家
Take me home now.
去电影院
Movie theater!
好了  大家都冷静点
Okay, everybody calm down.
解决方法很简单
There is a simple solution here.
拉杰  带我去火车玩具店
Raj, take me to the train store,
然后你们爱干吗干吗去吧
and then I don't care what you people do.
冲凉可舒爽
How was your shower?
不错  不错
It was good, good.
好奇问一句  你平时都几点睡觉呀
Just out of curiosity, what time do you usually go to bed?
我整晚都不睡的
Oh, I'm up all night.
我是个夜猫子
I'm like a possum.
你高中的时候不讨人喜欢  对吧
Boy, you were not liked in high school, were you?
还好吧
Not really.
那是我的高中年鉴吗
Is that my yearbook?
亲爱的莱纳德  你很擅长科学
"Dear Leonard, you're really good at science.
也许有天你能发明出
Maybe one day you'll come up
治疗呆子的良药
with a cure for being a dork".
这至少不是
Well, it wasn't spray-painting a Lightning Bolt
牛头不对马嘴的
on my briefcase, I can tell you that.
作为安慰  我可以告诉你
If it makes you feel any better,
唯一一个在我高中年鉴上留言的人是我妈
the only person who signed my yearbook was my mother.
亲爱的艾米
"Dear Amy,
自尊自爱和处女膜比交朋友和找乐子要珍贵百倍
self-respect and a hymen are better than friends and fun.
爱你的  妈妈
Love, Mom".
你可以把杰瑞枢纽站
Well, you can add Jerry's Junction
加到谢尔顿·库珀的
to the list of train stores
火车玩具店黑名单里了  我打死都不会再去了
Sheldon Cooper will never set foot in again.
今晚不顺吗  凯西·琼斯[美国偶像第九季季军]
Rough night, Casey Jones?
你是不知道呀
You don't know the half of it.
本来宣传的是说今晚将会是个
It was billed as a lively give-and-take
针对模型火车体积的优劣而进行的现场讨论会
on the merits of model train sizes.
可实际上只是为了唬那些
But it was actually a setup to intimidate
没定力的乡巴佬去买HO轨距的入门级火车
weak-minded spineless rubes into buying H-O starter sets.
你包里装的什么
What's in the bag?
关你屁事
I don't want to talk about it.
反正我不是被忽悠的
But it's not a spine, I'll tell you that.
我今晚过得很开心  莱纳德
Well, I had a delightful evening, Leonard.
我们以后要多这样聚聚
We should do this again sometime.
那是  常聚好
Ah, sure. That'd be nice.
很开心听你这么说
Glad to hear it.
我这周五需要有人陪我去参加
I need someone to accompany me to the wedding
莫瑞奈丽博士和古斯图弗迅博士的婚礼
of Dr. Moranelli and Dr. Gustufson this Friday.
他们有点像是灵长类部门里的
They're kind of the Brad and Angelina
布拉德和安吉丽娜一样
of the primatology department.
你带谢尔顿去不是更好吗
Wouldn't you rather bring Sheldon?
我也想  可我俩上次一起去参加的婚礼简直是场灾难
I would, but the last wedding we went to was a disaster.
他整场婚礼就像是个小孩一样
He behaved like a child the entire time.
不是我的错
Not my fault.
是你骗我说那里会有跟我年龄相当的科学家的
You said there'd be other scientists there my age.
无所谓了  反正你出局了  这次我带莱纳德去
Doesn't matter. You're out, he's in.
当初毕业舞会无人作伴
No date to the prom,
如今参加婚礼却有两人任选
two dates to a wedding.
真是造化弄人呀
Hmm, how times change.
嘿嘿  有人得去参加婚礼咯
Ha-ha, you have to go to a wedding.
我去开门
I'll get it!
你可以去开门吗
Could you get it?!
我不是刚说了我去开嘛
I just said I'm getting it!
好吧  我去开就是了
Fine, I'll get it!
我开
I got it!
我不想跟你吵架
I don't want to fight.
只不过你突然间说起要跟你妈一块住
I was just surprised when you sprung
把我给吓到了
the whole living-with-your-mom stuff on me.
对不起  我没事先问过你的意见
Yeah, well, I'm sorry I didn't run it by you first.
你在跟谁讲话呢
I don't know who you're talking to,
要不就进来说  要不就出去
but in or out!
别把门开着让虫子进来
We don't need bugs!
咱家会来虫子
The bugs only come here
是因为你是虫母
because you're their queen!
听着  这样怎么样
Listen, how about this.
在咱俩最终决定要住哪之前
Before we make any kind of decision
咱们先试婚一下
about where we live, we have a trial run.
在这住上一个周末  看看情况如何
Stay here for a weekend, see what it's like.
你妈不会有意见吗
And your mom would be okay with that?
当然不会
Sure she would.
妈  伯纳黛特在咱们家过周末  行吗
Ma, do you mind if Bernadette stays here this weekend?!
她都自动送上门了
Hey, if she's willing to give the milk away for free,
我还有什么好说的
who am I to say no?!
看见没  她不介意
See? She's good with it.
说实话  你以前整天带那个印度小子回家住
Frankly, after all your sleepovers
现在终于换成个女孩了  我放心多了
with the little brown boy, a girl is a big relief!
这么多年来  我都一直在犯一个严重的错误
All these years, I've been so wrong.
原来火车越小越好玩
The tinier the train, the more concentrated the fun.
你是个脑科学家
You're a brain scientist.
你可不可以给我解释一下  为什么
Can you explain to me why a brilliant man
这么聪明个人却喜欢玩玩具火车呢
likes playing with toy trains?
我必须把他的大脑切看研究一下才能回答你
Not without cutting his head open, no.
把我的眼睛化成埃及艳后怎么样
How about making my eyes like Cleopatra?
真的吗  就为了参加个婚礼
Really? For a wedding?
也许你说得对
Perhaps you're right.
我的颧骨和我那诱人的骨盆
My cheekbones and beckoning pelvis
对他们来说就已经够具冲击力的了
already have a certain "hello sailor" quality to them.
准备好了吗
Ready.
帅爆了
So handsome.
就跟007一样
Like James Bond.
他比007还给力  因为他更迷你
He's better than James Bond, because he's tinier.
给  把这个给我戴上
I got you this to give to me.
亲爱的  宾客参加婚礼
Oh, sweetie, guests don't normally
一般不戴胸花
wear corsages to a wedding.
去毕业舞会才戴
That's more of a prom thing.
我没去我的毕业舞会
I never went to my prom.
我妈付钱给我表哥让他带我去
My mom paid my cousin to take me,
但他用那钱买毒品去了
but he just used the money to buy drugs.
快帮她戴上胸花
Put the corsage on her.
艾米  这是为你准备的
Amy, this is for you.
你意思意思就好  回头我还是戴手腕上
When you're done copping a feel, that goes on my wrist.
全员上车
All aboard!
我正式宣布
It's official.
我现在是HO火车爱好者了
I'm an H-O trainiac.
晚餐进行得还不错
So, dinner went nice.
我想是吧
Yeah. Yeah, I guess.
你妈妈一直给你切肉的吗
Does your mother always cut your meat for you?
只是切肥肉而已
Only when it's fatty.
别吃醋  宝贝儿
Well, don't be jealous, babe.
以后你也能给我切
Someday you'll get to cut it for me.
伯纳黛特
Bernadette!
我又找到一个洗牙器刷头  你要用吗
I found the extra head for the Waterpik if you want to use it!
不用了  沃罗威茨夫人
I'm okay, Mrs. Wolowitz.
你确定吗
You sure?!
我刚洗出来半块胸肉
I just squirted half a brisket outta my teeth!
老妈  留点私人空间好吗
Hey, Ma, how about a little privacy?!
唔  我懂的
Oh, I know what that means!
甚好甚好
Hubba-hubba!
老天
Oh, God.
别担心  会没事的
Relax, it'll be fine.
好吧
Okay.
你们亲热完了和我说一声
Let me know when you're done canoodling!
到时给你老妈子搓搓脚丫子
Mommy needs a foot rub!
你想去跳舞吗
Would you like to dance?
不用了
No, thank you.
我真不是个擅长跳舞的人
I'm really not much of a dancer.
那这么说来你在健谈方面
You're not exactly winning any trophies
也失败的很
as a conversationalist, either.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
新娘新郎看起来很开心
The bride and groom seem happy.
他们当然开心了
Why shouldn't they be?
他们马上就可以进行
They have a feverish night of
社会公认的激情交配之夜了
socially-approved copulation ahead of them.
在某些文化习俗里  我们要站在洞房外
In some cultures, we'd stand outside of their bedroom
欢呼他们达到高潮
cheering as they achieved orgasm.
这听起来要搞到很晚
That sounds like a late night,
而我第二天一早要工作  所以...
and I have work in the morning, so...
莱纳德  也许你没注意到
Leonard, you may not have noticed,
但我在努力逗你开心
but I am being a delight here.
而你却觉得待不下去了
And you're not holding up your end of the evening.
不好意思  只是这场婚礼让我想起
Oh, sorry. This wedding just reminds me
我那所谓的远在天边的女朋友
of my kinda-sorta girlfriend 9,000 miles away.
我那个所谓的男朋友  现在正沉迷于玩具火车中
I have a kinda-sorta boyfriend who's playing with a model train right now,
我还没跟你吐槽呢
you don't hear me bitching about it.
莱纳德  友情提示一下  装忧郁
Leonard, a word of advice-- moody self-obsession
只适合那些玩吉他
is only attractive in men who can play guitar
跟身高比你有优势的男生
and are considerably taller than you.
我不忧郁
I'm not moody.
我很风趣
I'm fun.
那你有什么证据证明吗
You have any evidence to support that statement?
我就和你一样风趣
Well, hey, I'm just as much fun as you are.
是吗  你会在手指上画个小胡子
Really? Are you willing to draw a mustache on your finger
用来活跃气氛吗
as a conversational icebreaker?
我就会
I am.
好吧  你有什么建议
Okay, fine, what do you suggest?
我们刚刚大吃了一顿
We just had a lovely meal,
而现在乐队正嗨得火热
the band... is on fire...
你旁边是位漂亮的女士
and you're sitting next to a beautiful woman
还浓妆艳抹地涂得像个妓女
wearing whorish makeup.
我们干嘛不去跳个舞
Why don't we head out on the dance floor
看我能不能跳得一身湿
and see if I can sweat through these dress shields.
再强调一下  我真的不擅长跳舞
Once again, I-I'm really not much of a dancer.
别担心
Don't worry...
我来领舞
I'll lead.
著名的"小鸡舞"
霍华德
Howard?
准备好觉觉了吗
Ready for bed?
没有  我要刷牙  但你妈妈
No. I need to brush my teeth, but your mother's
已经霸占了厕所快一个小时了
been in the bathroom for, like, an hour. Oh.
嗯  她有时候那方面的确有点困难  等下
Yeah, she sometimes has problems doing her business. Hang on.
妈  放弃吧
Ma, give up!
今晚你没戏了
Tonight's not your night!
你怎么知道  我才刚坐下
You don't know that! I just sat down!
得了  歇会吧
Come on, take a break!
伯纳黛特要刷牙
Bernadette needs to brush her teeth!
她可以进来刷牙啊
She can come in and brush her teeth!
我又不介意
I'm not embarrassed!
问题解决了
Problem solved.
才没有  我才不要进去
No, it's not. I'm not going in there.
没事的  亲爱的
Oh, come on, honey.
她只是坐那看杂志罢了
She's just sitting in there reading a magazine.
你什么都看不到的
You can't see anything.
我向来都是直接进去的
I go in all the time.
哈哈  "鹰"总算降落了
Ha! The eagle has landed!
而且是降落在"大海"中
And we have splashdown.
稍等下啊  我去点蜡烛
Wait here, I'm gonna go light a candle.
然后我们来激情爱爱
And then we make passionate love.
快了  马上到了
There we go, last floor.
我真不明白怎么回事
I just can't figure out what happened.
我把左腿放进去  再拿出来
I put my left leg in, I took my left leg out,
再放进去  然后什么东西就噼啪乱响
I put my left leg in, and something just snapped.
变戏法不适合你这老胳膊老腿了
The hokey pokey is a young man's game.
今晚真的很开心
I did have a great time.
谢谢你提醒我
Thank you for reminding me
偶尔找找乐子也是可以的
it's okay to have fun once in a while.
不客气
You're welcome.
再谢谢你掰下冰天鹅的头
And also for breaking the head off the ice swan
让我敷着拉伤的腹股沟
so I could hold it against my pulled groin.
我擅长空间推理
I excel at spatial reasoning,
当时预感到天鹅脖子那优美的弧度
and I had a hunch that the graceful slope of its neck
能恰好做你生殖器的支架
would cradle your genitals nicely.
明白  再次感谢
Well, okay. Again, thank you.
再次不用谢
And again, you're welcome.
想进来喝杯茶吗
Want to come in, have a cup of tea?
不用了  谢谢  我该回家了
No, thanks. I'm gonna head home.
好吧  晚安
'Kay. Well, good night.
晚安
Good night.
小米  嗨  婚礼怎样
Ames, hi. How was the wedding?
棒极了  直到我不小心让莱纳德爱上我
Great. Until I accidentally made Leonard fall in love with me.
进来吧  我们得聊聊
Come in, let's talk.
想来杯酒吗
Do you want a glass of wine?
酒就是我陷入此困境的罪魁之一
Wine is one of the reasons I'm in this fix.
还有个祸首就是这该死的骨盆
That and this dang pelvis.
好吧  抱歉  到底怎么回事
Okay, I'm sorry, what exactly happened?
这是不可避免的
The inevitable--
他思念女友  孤独又脆弱
he was lonely and vulnerable from missing his girlfriend,
而我迷人又支持他
while I was charming, supportive
还有  面对现实吧  穿着这身裙子
and, let's face it, in this dress,
我就是麦当娜和浪女的绝妙组合
the perfect combination of Madonna and whore.
天哪  他对你下手了吗
Oh, God, did he make a move on you?
没  但这只是时间问题
No, but it's only a matter of time.
我怎么会没早料到呢
How could I have not seen this coming?
现在我得伤了这小糊涂虫的心了
Now I'm gonna have to break the little sad sack's heart.
没事  我相信他挺得过去
Yeah, I'm sure he'll be okay.
佩妮  我最多只是知道
Oh, Penny, much as I would treasure knowing that
我们俩被同一个男人玷污了
the two of us had been defiled by the same man,
莱纳德完全提不起我的性致
Leonard just doesn't get my motor running.
那你想怎么做呢
So, um, what are you gonna do?
你想让我去告诉莱纳德  让他好受点吗
Do you want me to talk to Leonard, let him down easy?
不  就让他痴心妄想一晚吧
No. I'll let him have tonight.
然后明天早上
Then in the morning,
我会给他发电邮  让他知道
I'll send him an e-mail letting him know
这具身体无法成为他的极乐仙境
this body is never gonna be his wonderland.
老实说  你的机会还比他大呢
I mean, frankly, you've got a better shot than he does.
莱纳德
Leonard.
快看
Check it out.
我买了辆N轨距火车
I bought an N-gauge locomotive.
HO轨距的一半
Half the size of H-O.
看  正好能放我嘴里
Look, it fits in my mouth.
看来你今晚过得很愉快
Sounds like you had a great night.
没错
I did.
-你呢  -也不错
- How was yours? - Not bad.
跟艾米在一起比我预想的更有乐趣
I had a lot more fun with Amy than I thought I would.
你这样说到底指什么
What exactly do you mean by that?
事实证明  她的确懂得
Well, it turns out she really knows
怎样帮助男人放松和愉悦
how to help a guy loosen up and have a good time.
虽然老实说  我下阴被磨损了点
Although, truth be told, my groin's a little worse for wear.
你干嘛啊
Why did you do that?
我是要告诉你  她不属于你
To send a message: she is not for you.
什么
What?
她不属于你
Not for you!
早啊  帅哥
Good morning, handsome.
早  妈妈
Morning, Mom.
是我
It's me.
没错  是你  你早上真漂亮
Yes, it is, and you're so pretty in the morning.
我和你妈妈做了早餐
Your mom and I made you breakfast.
你们俩相处得不错吗
So you guys are getting along?
差不多吧
Yeah, I guess.
霍华德  我们俩是不同类型的人
We're very different people, Howard,
交流起来需要点技巧
so communication's a little tricky.
他喜欢薄烤饼吗
Does he like the pancakes?!
他还没吃呢
He didn't try them yet!
有黄油吗
Is there any butter?
这是黄油味糖浆
It's butter-flavored syrup.
你们在说什么
So, what's the word?!
他要黄油
He wants butter!
那是黄油味糖浆
It's butter-flavored syrup!
我刚跟他说了
I just told him that!
我不用黄油了
I don't need any butter.
你要黄油  我就给你去拿黄油
If you want butter, I'll get you butter.
看来哥只能自己切了
Well, I guess I'll cut these by myself.